Hello everyone,
welcome back to our channel.
I'm back with another interesting topic on the TSA Automation Playlist
.
So let's continue our topic on test
automation
barriers
.  Let's look at the next obstacle, called 'get
s number'
.
Now this
particular
restriction is related to XML file
automation
.
So
what we need to
do here is
download this XML file called catalog
,
save it manually,
then
read that file and extract the integer including the prefix of this
particular ID
or
name
through TSA
.  Okay.    Once
you have it, you need to
enter it into this specific text box
.  Okay.
So if I click on this
catalog
link
, it will
download the file and
save it to my Downloads folder.    Once
that's
done,
let's see what's in this file, what we need to take out, and what we need to enter into this text box.
Okay.  The file has been
downloaded
, now
let's look at our Downloads folder,
there we
can find the catalog file.  This is
an XML file.
Now if I
open this up, you'll
see there are different nodes,
all within
this
catalog
.
The node inside this has a number
ID, a prefix
number,
and a jer (jer
), and there
are some records here.  In this, we
need to search for an ID with the name sue,
then
we
need to take the prefix and number within it.  Okay.
Then you need to write this together in that
specific
text
box
.  Okay.    If
I copy this
prefix and
come here.
Okay.  This is
part of the number.    The
second
part is that number
.  Okay.  So if
you
write the whole number with the prefix,
this
particular
automation
ban
will be lifted
, which we need to do using TSCA
.  Okay.
So there are two parts to this
ban
,
let's see how to complete this in TSCA.
Okay.  Now let's
return to our TSA workspace.
First, let's create our
modules
.  There will be two
different
modules here
.  Okay.    The
reason for that is that
a module
is associated with an XML file,
because we will
scan the XML file and
create the module
, the next
module will
be the application i.e. that text box.  Okay.
I'm going to create a
folder to put these two blocks in
,
then I'm going to rename this
folder
with the number of this block
.  Okay.
Now we're going to
come here and rename this
.
Now let's
scan the XML file first
.  Okay.
Now you can scan the XML
file using a
different
option
.
So, you
don't need to use the 'application' option here.
We need to go to 'more'
,
where we will see 'file scan'
.  Okay.
This will allow you to
scan the XML file
.  So, we
select 'file scan'
.  Then this
dialog
box will come up,
in which we need to select the XML
file
.  So, let's
select this and
click 'open'
.  Okay.
It
will create a module.
Okay.  This is the module containing the XML
file
and its
contents
.
Now the next module we
need to scan
is the application.  So,
this time we will scan the 'application'
option
and select the
Chrome browser here
.  Then
we will select the text box here
.  Okay.  That's all
we
need here
.
Then, I'm going to call this
'number'
.  Text
box.  Okay.
Then, I'm
going to close this.    I'm
going to save this.  Okay.
So this is
the file
and this is the
text box,
now let's create our
test case
.  So, let's
go to our obstacles and
create them here
.  Then, let's drag these
two
blocks
here
.
Okay.  First we'll drag '
catalog request'
,
then we'll drag our text
box
.  Okay.
Now
let's look at this test case.
Okay.  Here we
need to enter the number,
but before that we
need to extract the number.  Okay.
Before that, we need to open the XML
file
,
because only if it is
opened
can we extract any specific node.  Okay.
For that we
need to add another module here, it is called '
open create XML file'
, this will be our
first step
.
So, I'll pull this here
This requires a
resource name
.  So, let's
call it 'catalog',
then we
need to give the path to the file.  So,
I will search for and select the file
path
, and then I
can pass the same 'catalog' as a resource reference.
Here, it will send the note after it
is opened
,
after which
we
can go to the respective node,
here we have to go into the ID
.  Okay.
Also,
we
know we're looking for an ID named Sue,
right?
Instead of verifying, I'm going to turn it
into a constraint
so that it
selects that specific node
, right?  Then
we
need a prefix and a number, so I'm
going to call this 'pre'.  I'll call this '
num'
, and
I'm going to buffer these two values
.  Okay.  After buffering these
two
values
, you will have those
numbers
, and now
I
can use them to enter them into the text box
.  Okay.  So
here I'm going to
have two buffers
.
First there
will be a prefix,
then there
will be a number.  Okay.
So this will
basically
concatenate these two.  This
will be entered into the text box one by one
.  Okay.  That's all we have to do in this
particular
task
.
Now let's change the work
state
to 'completed'
.
Now we are ready to run this
particular
test case
.  Okay.    Let's
run this and
see if we can complete the automation in this text box.
Okay.
As you can see,
it
has completed the task by inputting both the prefix and the number into the text box
.  This way
you
can browse through various XML-related modules
or extract nodes by going to a
specific
node
.  Also,
you can use the
scan
feature to scan any XML file
, so that
all the
nodes are
automatically
available in your module,
then
you can
easily
check all the nodes and
extract the required node or a specific child node
, where
you can get the information you
need and
enter it into your application.
That's all for this video.    If
you have
any
questions
,
please
ask in the comments
.  If you liked this video
, please
subscribe to our channel.
Thanks for watching, see you
in the next video
.